Jieyun Chen

Mobile: 0413 961 852 Visa Type: Permanent Resident

Email: cheruby.chen@gmail.com Github: https://github.com/jieyunchen

Summary

Jieyun, an ISTQB certified tester and IBM certified specialist, has over 12 years' experience in IT industry. As a technical lead at IBM, Jieyun has led a team of 4 engineers for test execution, created test automation framework with Selenium WebDriver for IBM High-end Storage DS8000 web UI testing, built baseline test automation framework in Python and enhanced storage interoperability test automation framework by integrating testbed configuration scripts and error inject scripts to the continuous integration platform. Prior to IBM, Jieyun was as an embedded software developer in ZTE.

Skills

- Test methodologies, execution and automation development.
- Selenium WebDriver, Selenium Grid, POM, Page Factory
- BDD, Cucumber, Gherkin
- REST-assured
- Amazon AWS, IBM Softlayer
- Git, Maven, Jenkins, CI/CD
- Java, Python
- SQL, Linux
- Agile
- JUnit & TestNG
- SAN, FC/iSCSI protocol, VMware vSphere
- IBM Enterprise Storage DS8000, IBM mainframe S390

Employment

International Business Machines (IBM)

2010.04 to 2019.06 2018.04 to 2019.06

> Test Automation Developer, SAN Storage Interoperability

Test the interoperability between IBM disk storage systems with third party hardwares and softwares in Storage Area Network(SAN) environment. The matrix includes various operation system(e.g., Windows, Linux, Vmware), application software(e.g., Oracle, Veritas), network protocol(e.g., Fibre Channel, iSCSI) and hardware(e.g., storage system, switch and server).

- Develop SAN testbed configuration and error injection scripts for storage interoperability test automation framework and enhance the framework by integrating those scripts to unified continuous integration platform Jenkins.
- Setup and configure SAN testbed.
- Run IO and error injection test.
- Pass VMware/Veritas/Oracle VM Certification test for IBM Storage.
- ➤ Tech Lead/QA Engineer/Automation Developer, DS8000 GUI FVT 2015.04 to 2018.03 IBM System Storage DS8000 is a high-performance, high-capacity series of disk storage system. The objective of DS8000 GUI Functional Verification Test(FVT) is to verify the new function of DS8000 Web User Interface(UI) against the design document and verify the new function of DS8000 Web UI does not cause previously available functions to regress and does not adversely affect any other new functions.

- Develop DS8000 web UI test automation framework and integrate the framework to Jenkins in order to achieve continuous integration for DS8000 web UI development by using the following skills:
 - ✓ BDD/Cucumber/Gherkin Build up DS8000 web UI Behaviour Driven Development(BDD) test automation framework by Cucumber. Translate web UI regression test cases to the feature file using Gherkin language in order to enhance the communication among developer, QA and product manager.
 - ✓ Selenium WebDriver use Selenium WebDriver to automate DS8000 web UI regression test and implement Page Object Model(POM) with Page Factory in this framework.
 - ✓ Maven use Maven to define project structure, dependencies, build and test automation.
 - √ JUnit use JUnit Annotations to implement JUnit test and use JUnit assert for the test validation.
 - ✓ Git use GitHub to manage DS8000 web UI test automation code.
 - ✓ Xvfb/ffmpeg use "Xvfb" to run web UI automation test on a "headless" server, use "ffmpeg" to capture every moment during the test and output a video of the execution.
 - ✓ Jenkins integrate web UI test automation framework to Jenkins to achieve continuous integration for DS8000 web UI development.
- DS8000 GUI function verification test, stress test and regression test plan/test case design, test
 execution, test status report and defect open/track.
- As GUI FVT tech lead, drive team to improve test process, track project status and resolve impediments.
- Tech Lead/QA Engineer/Automation Developer, DS8000 Baseline 2010.04 to 2015.03 DS8000 Baseline test is an initial smoke test to catch core code breakage at its early stage in order to ensure basic functions are working normally before releasing to a wider test community.
- Develop baseline test automation framework in Python to build baseline test execution platform with which testers can execute baseline test and collect logs automatically.
- Setup & configure Baseline test bed and execute build verification test to catch the core code breakage at the early stage in order to prevent Function Verification Test and System Level Test from being impacted by broken code.
- Baseline test plan/test case design, test execution, test status report and defect open/track.
- IBM Enterprise Storage DS8000, IBM mainframe server and open server daily maintenance.
- As baseline tech lead, keep good communication with stakeholders and continuously lead team to improve test quality & efficiency.

ZTE Corporation R&D Center

2007.07 to 2010.03

- Software Developer, ZTE passive optical access product ZXA10 C300 Development ZXA10 C300 is the industry's first large capacity optical access platform oriented to 10G PON which offers ultra-fast bandwidth and meets the requirements of big video and universal broadband services.
 - Design and implement different failover/failback solutions based on various scenarios.
- Design and execute test cases, perform unit and integration test and resolve defects.
- Shorten failover/failback switch time to make performance better than competitors' products
- Develop GPON line card MAC driver in C by integrating vendor's MAC chip software and perform functional verification test, stress test and performance test to find bugs.
- Track vendor's defects and help vendor to resolve defects by re-producing the errors and capturing the logs.

Education

Huazhong University of Science and Technology

2001.07 to 2007.06

- Master, Computer Software and Theory
- Bachelor, Computer Science and Technology

Certificate

- ISTQB Certified Tester, Foundation Level. Certificate No. 18-CTFL-137278-06
- IBM Certified Specialist, High-End Disk for Open Systems

Language

- English. Second Language. Professional working proficiency
- Chinese. Native Language

Patent

- EP2528271A1. Method, passive optical network system and optical line terminal for enabling distributed protection. Jieyun Chen, Jinshu Lu, Wenjie Huang.
- CN200910160883. A Dynamic Serial Number Management in PON System. Jinshu Lu, Jieyun Chen.
- CN200610166584. Self-Adapted Secure Group Communication System based on distributed management Infrastructure. Hai Jin, Deqing Zou, Yunfa Li, Jieyun Chen, Huaizhen Jiang, Weizhong Qiang.

Publication

- CI Practice in Jenkins. Jieyun Chen. IBM developerWorks, 2017.
- CI Practice in DS8000 GUI Development. Jieyun Chen. IBM developerWorks, 2016.
- A Method to Trigger Alarm for Single Peer-to-Peer Remote Copy Path. **Jieyun Chen**, Weiwei Ni, Zhiying Yu. IBM Published Disclosure CN820130964, 2013.
- A method to backup & recover logical configuration for the storage system. **Jieyun Chen**, Hongfan Liu, Zhiying Yu. IBM Published Disclosure CN820110874, 2011.
- Daonity Grid Security from Two Levels of Virtualization. Haibo Chen, Jieyun Chen, Wenbo Mao, Fan Yan. Elsevier Information Security Technical Report, 2007.(ACM Indexed)
- A Scalable Secure Service Scheme for Group Communication in Grid. Yunfa Li, Hai Jin, Deqing Zou, Jieyun Chen. Proceedings of Thirty-first International computer Software and Application Conference(COMPSAC'07), 2007. (El Indexed)
- A Digital Signature Mechanism and Authentication Scheme for Group Communication in Grid. Yunfa Li, HaiJin, Deqing Zou, Jieyun Chen, Zongfen Han. Proceeding of the 4th international conference of autonomic and trusted computing Springer Press, Hong Kong, China, 2007.(El Indexed)

Award

IBM System Outstanding Technical Achievement Award for Leadership in Storage Development